" ["Love You Want"
By Wailing Souls]
' Ah, if I give the love
you want you won't forget '
' Girl, if I give the love
' If I give the love you want
you won't forget '
' Girl, if I give the love
you want you won't forget '
' Come on to me, baby '
' And take my blues away '
' What I need to see now '
' Is brighter days '
' I want to take away
my dark skies '
' Take away my tears '
' Take away my sufferin' '
' People feel
for all these years '
' If I give the love you want
you won't forget '
' Girl, if I give the love
you want you won't forget '
- [Children Laughing]
- ' If I give the love you want you won't forget '
' Girl, if I give the love
you want you won't forget '
' Let this love light shine '
' Let it in your soul '
- [Kids Shouting, Chattering]
- ' Steady on forever '
' It's time to take control '
On your mark, get set, go!
' We don't need no darkness
We don't need no fear '
' We don't need no sadness '
' It's already bright here '
[Cheering]
' Don't get upset
if you ain't got nobody '
if you have no fun '
- ' Don't get angry '
- ' Don't get upset when you wake up '
- ' In the morning '
- [Man] Hey, Derice, where you runnin', man?
- Yeah.
- Mornin'.
- How are ya?
- '... new day life's just begun '
' Ooo, yeah '
' Give thanks and praises '
- Hey, there.
- Derice.
' Love is comin' your way '
' Don't get upset
if you ain't got nobody '
if you have no fun '
' Don't get angry '
' Don't get upset when
you wake up in the mornin' '
' 'Cause every new day
life's just begun '
' Ooh, yeah '
- [People Chattering]
- ' Give thanks and praises '
- Mornin'.
- Faster, Bannock, faster.
Come on, child.
You have an Olympics to get to.
Handsome as a lion, that one.
I could watch that backside all day.
[Laughing]
Come on!
' If I give the love you want
you won't forget '
' Girl, if I give the love
you want you won't forget '
' Take away my sadness '
' Take away my fears "
[People Chattering]
[Chattering Continues]
Hey, Sanka, this
steering wheel is finished.
All right, team, let's get ready
for the pre-race cheer.
- Ready? Ready?
- Yes, sir! Yes, sir!
All right.
One, two, three, toot!
[Chanting] Who's the captain of our crew?
Who's a friend to me and you?
Kinda nice, good-lookin' too.
Sanka, Sanka! Yea, Sanka!
[Laughs]
Get back to work.
[Man] Who's the big, hot bag of air
who doesn't have to comb his hair?
Who doesn't bathe and doesn't care?
Sanka! Sanka!
- Yea, Sanka! Hey!
- Sanka!
What's happenin', star?
Where you been, man?
You almost missed my all-time,
world record seventh derby in a row.
Easy, Rasta.
- I'm not gonna forget my best friend
on his day of days. - [Boy] Derice.
My grandfather says you're definitely
going to make it to the Olympics.
He says you're even faster
than your father.
- [Boy #2] Do it for Jamaica.
- You know what my grandfather says?
- [Together] What?
- Get back to work!
- Booie, booie!
- [Protesting]
Good luck, man. I'll see you
at the finish line, all right?
[Laughing]
- Hi, Momma Coffie.
- Hi, Derice.
- Derice, is Sanka ready?
- Who knows?
That boy's never ready. He's a lazy,
crazy, sorry, no-good bag of bones.
- [Laughing]
- So what you laughing at?
All pushcarts
to the start position.
- Ready, little man?
- Ready, big man.
Kiss the lucky egg.
- [Crowd Cheering, Shouting]
- Let's go.
- On your marks.
- Feel the rhythm, feel the rhyme.
Get on up,
it's pushcart time!
- And go!
- [Horn Blaring]
Go!
[Sanka] Here we go, Winston!
Me rocket has been launched!
Hey, pokey!
Where'd you get that cart?
Clear out! Move out!
Look out! [Laughs]
Sanka Coffie!
Pushcart champion!
- Pushcart champion!
- Get away! Get away!
[Sanka]
Hey, grandma! Outta my way!
Hey, Sunday driver! Make room
for the Rasta Rockett! Make room!
- Sanka! Four more carts left.
- Pee wee, move! Move out!
[Sanka] I love Jamaica
and Jamaica loves me!
Champion! Champion!
You can't mess with the best!
- Move over! Move over!
- [Winston] Get away! Get off me!
- Come on, Sanka, get...
- Get him! Get him!
One more time, Sanka.
Go, go, go!
[Sanka]
Yes! We win! Oh! Oh, no!
- No!
- [Screaming]
Jump, Winston! Jump! Ohhh!
Uhhh! Sanka!
[Chicken Clucking]
[Derice]
Move, man, move, move, move!
Sanka. You dead?
Yeah, man.
[Groans]
And where do you think you're going?
You caught me.
[Laughs]
- You have papers to grade.
- I'm just getting in one last run.
Mm-hmm.
Can't believe the trials
are finally here.
- You nervous?
- I'm not nervous. I'm ready.
I've been ready for this day
my whole life.
I don't care how fast they run.
I'm gonna run faster.
I don't care
how much they want it.
I want it more.
I'm goin' to the Olympics, baby.
I feel it.
I'm gonna win the gold.
Derice, are you nervous?
I'm terrified.
[Laughing]
It's my turn, Joy.
It's my turn.
[Man On P.A.] Ladies and gentlemen,
welcome to the final event...
of today's Olympic tryouts.
- [Crowd Chattering]
- We have now come to the
main event of our games,
the running
of the 100-meter finals.
We've had a most
successful afternoon...
and I'd like to congratulate
all of the athletes...
who have participated
in today's events.
- You sure no one can beat him?
- Oh, sure, I'm sure.
I'm just a little concerned
about that big baldy.
[Growling]
Let me first congratulate our athletes
on a splendid performance.
And let me remind them that
only the top four finishers...
will earn the right
to represent Jamaica...
in the forthcoming
summer games in Seoul, Korea.
- W-Wait. You're Derice Bannock, right?
- That's me.
Oh. I hope I make the team.
It would be a real honor
to run with you.
- Good luck to you.
Derice Bannock.
Hey, good luck to you too.
Runners, take your marks!
Get set!
[Starter's Pistol Fires]
[Crowd Cheering]
[Derice] Mr. Coolidge, please.
You have to run the race over.
[Coolidge] I'm sorry, Derice,
nothing can be done.
But I was born
to compete in the Olympics.
Then you're gonna have to work
on your boxing or your cycling.
Those are the only other two sports
in which Jamaica competes.
I am not a boxer.
I am a runner.
And it wasn't fair.
It rarely is, my boy.
It rarely is.
Well, Poppa, what do I do now?
Look, Derice.
Let it go, will you? Let it go.
You will have
another chance in four years.
Yeah.
Mr. Coolidge, who's the other man
in the picture with my father?
Irving Blitzer.
He's an American who lives here.
Unless, of course,
he's been arrested or shot.
- Excuse me?
- Well, he's a bookie now.
Takes his bets in a small pool hall
just past Sandy Bay.
Isn't that a gold medal
around his neck?
Oh, yeah. That lunatic
was an Olympic bobsledder...
who tried to get your father
to switch sports.
He had some theory about using
track sprinters to push the bobsled.
Some ridiculous thing like that.
Can you imagine,
a Jamaican bobsledder?
- And you sure this man,
he lives on the island?
- Oh, yes.
- Mr. Coolidge, thanks a lot.
- Good, Derice.
- Oh. Could I borrow this picture?
- Bring it back.
Yes. Thanks a lot,
Mr. Coolidge.
- Oh. Just one more thing.
- Hmm?
What's a bobsled?
That's a bobsled!
Oh! So a bobsled is
a pushcart with no wheels.
- That's what it looks like here.
- Let me see that.
All right. "The key elements
for a successful sled team...
are a steady driver and three strong
runners to push off down the ice."
Ice! Ice!
Well... it's kind of
a winter sport, you know.
- You mean winter as in ice?
- Maybe.
You mean winter as in igloos
and Eskimos and penguins and ice?
- Possibly.
- See ya.
- Where you goin'?
- I'm gonna take a hot bath.
I'm gettin' cold just thinkin'
about all this ice.
No, man! You're gonna be
part of my bobsled team.
What you need me for?
Who... is the best
pushcart driver...
- In all of Jamaica?
- You're lookin' at him!
- Then you're gonna do it?
- No!
Hey, man, you could be famous.
You could have your picture
on a Wheaties box.
But you said no, and that's all right
because I don't need ya.
Everybody is gonna want to be
on my bobsled team.
Look, star, let me tell you
a little somethin', all right?
When you need something from me,
you don't have to hand me a bunch of lines.
All you have to do is
look at me in the eye and say,
"Sanka, you are my best friend.
We've been through a whole heap together
and I really, really need you."
Sanka, you're right.
And you are my best friend.
And we've been through a whole lot together.
- Heap. Heap.
- Sorry, man. A whole heap together.
And I really, really need you.
- And I really, really need you.
- Forget it!
- But you just said if I said that, man...
- All right, all right,
all right.
All right, man.
[Sanka] So, let's talk
about this "billsled" team.
- [Derice] No. Bobsled team.
- Whoever.
[Sanka] Now about the Wheaties box.
I'm gonna be on it by myself, right?
No, man, you're gonna be
on it with me.
[Man On Radio] And down the stretch
they come! Tumbleweed is holding on...
- As Captain Video is still running on the outside.
- Yes, Tumbleweed, yes!
...is dropping back as Tumbleweed holds the rail.
- Come on! That's it!
Good Tumbleweed!
- Tumbleweed is slowing!
- No, Tumbleweed, no! Bad Tumbleweed!
- What are you doin'?
- Tumbleweed can't hold it as
he gets pinned against the rail.
Don't do that!
Let him out!
- Don't! I need this one!  - Tumbleweed is
running gamely, but Captain Video...
- Seems just a little bit too strong.
- Please! Come on!
- Here they come! Yes!
- No!
Tumbleweed can't hold it
as Captain Video takes charge.
- And it's Brewster finishing in second.
Susan's Pride... - What?
finishes third and Tumbleweed
is nowhere in sight.
But my, oh, my, the
odds-on favorite showed
his true colors with
that late stretch run.
- Uh-huh.  - Tumbleweed held on
momentarily, but realistically,
only a fool would put
their money on Tumbleweed.
- That horse had no chance whatsoev...
- Uh-huh! Uh-huh! Uh-huh!
Uh-huh! Uh-huh!
That guy won two gold medals?
I think so.
[Sighs]
That's Tumbleweed gone.
Okay, next race.
Excuse, me.
Are you Mr. Irving Blitzer?
Well, that depends
on who's asking.
My name is Derice Bannock.
This is my teammate, Sanka Coffie.
Greetings, sled god.
We were just wondering
if you'd be interested...
in coaching the first
Jamaican bobsled team.
Derice, remember the radio?
Radio?
Stick. Shooting
with the stick. Let's go!
Let's go, Derice!
Come on, coach.
Just help me get started.
[Derice Groans]
- Oh!
- Greetings, sled god.
- Sorry to bother you, but you're the
only one who can help us.  - Get out! Get out!
[Sighs, Groans]
[Toilet Flushing]
- Go away.
- Okay.
Nice to meet you!
- Maybe today is a bad day.
- Yeah.
I'll come back tomorrow.
And the next day. And the next day.
- No! Look, whatever your name is...
- Derice.
All right, Derice. Let me lay out
some difficulties for you.
Snow. You don't have any.
It's 900 degrees out there.
Time. You don't have any.
The Olympics are in three months.
And me. You don't have me.
As far as I'm concerned, the sport
of bobsledding no longer exists.
I don't want to do it,
I don't want to coach it,
and most of all,
and I mean most of all,
I don't want to be within
2,000 miles of anyone who does.
Now, did you follow all that?
Then how come you still have
that poster on the wall?
Is that what's bothering you?
There. Is that better?
Are you happy?
Like I said...
my name is Derice Bannock.
I'm Ben Bannock's son.
I haven't seen this picture
in 20 years.
Huh. Would you look at me then?
Whoo. Would you look at me now.
Please, Mr. Blitzer,
just give me a chance.
If I don't have what it takes,
we'll forget the whole thing.
Believe me, kid,
you do not have what it takes.
- But you thought my father did.
- Your father was one of...
the toughest competitors I ever saw.
He ran the 100 meters in ten-flat.
Well, I run it in nine-nine.
Come on. Coach me.
Sorry.
You're a couple decades late.
Oh, I see. It might be easy
for you to walk away from me,
Mr. Blitzer, but you can't
walk away from this:
Twenty years ago
you came down here to see...
if you could make a Jamaican sprinter
into a bobsledder,
and you never got that chance.
Look at me, Mr. Blitzer.
I'm your chance.
Take it.
[Exhaling]
- [Crowd Chattering]
- " [Reggae]
All right.
Everyone quiet down.
Nice group here.
Now, for two of you lucky people,
our trip to the Olympics
starts right now.
And I want to introduce you...
to Mr. Irving Blitzer...
who's going to be
our expert bobsled coach.
Sanka. Hit it, man.
You're on the air, sled god.
Gentlemen, a bobsled
is a simple thing.
[Man]
Yeah, so's a toilet!
[Crowd Laughing]
Thank you. Thank you very much.
Basically, what you're looking to do...
is get your sorry rear ends from the top
of an icy chute to the bottom.
You're ziggin', you're zaggin'.
It's the biggest, coldest
roller coaster you've ever been on.
Ice.
Oooh. Ooh.
[Chuckles]
[Irv]
Oh, yeah. Oh, yeah.
I almost forgot, uh...
One minor drawback
to this delightful winter sport...
is the high-speed crash.
That hurt. Ah.
Always remember, your bones
will not break in a bobsled.
No, no. They shatter.
Eee!
So... who wants in?
Look. Baldy's here.
Glad you could make it, man.
- Don't touch me!
- No problem.
- So what's your name?
- Yul Brenner.
Well, it's good to have you
as a teammate, Brenner.
Let's get one thing straight,
Bannock.
We may be on the same team,
but I am no one's teammate.
- Long as you come here to bobsled...
- Hey, listen, man,
the only reason why I come here...
is to get off
of this stinkin' island.
If I have to take one of those
bobsleds to do it, then all right.
- No problem.
- [Irv] Ah, yes.
Yes, I have a problem. There's
no such thing as a three-man sled.
You're one Jamaican short.
Hey.
The meeting start yet?
Uh-oh.
You! I'll kill you.
- [Derice] Wait! Hold on!
- College boy, I'll kill you!
[Sanka] Hey, think, man, think!
Easy! Whoa! Down, boy!
[Men Shouting, Chair Clattering]
Kill him
and we don't have a team.
I'm not ridin'
in the same sled as that.
He tripped me too, you know.
But in case you haven't noticed,
there's no one else here.
- You're crowdin' me, slinky head.
- [Chuckling]
Slinky head.
That's a good one.
- What are you laughing about?
- Nothing.
If it wasn't for you, rich boy,
I'd be in the Olympics right now.
I don't know what you all are arguing
about 'cause Derice was gonna...
- Beat both of your butts anyway.
- What are you talkin' about?
- How 'bout I beat your butt right now?
- How 'bout I draw a line...
down the middle of your head
so it looks like a butt?
[Chuckling]
Forget it, man, I'm gone.
[Derice]
Fine. Stay here on the island.
We're going to Canada.
All right. I'll do it.
But you better tell
this mama's boy...
to stay the hell away from me.
You understand?
No problem.
Hey, Irv.
Say hello to the first...
Jamaican bobsled team.
Oh, goody.
Gentlemen,
this... is a bobsled.
Sort of.
- All right, here's what we're gonna do. Yul...
- Don't touch me.
Of course. Sorry. You're
gonna be the second middleman.
You're strong, you're fast
and you're gonna love that seat.
Junior,
you're the first middleman.
You're quick, you're sharp.
Hop in. Sanka.
- I know. I'm the driver, right?
- No, you're the brakeman.
- No, no, I'm the driver.
- No, you're not. You're the brakeman.
- I'm the driver.
- You're not. You're the brakeman.
You don't understand.
I am Sanka Coffie.
I'm the best pushcart driver
in all of Jamaica.
I must drive.
Do you dig where I'm coming from?
- Yeah, I dig where you're coming from.
- Good.
Now dig where I'm coming from.
I'm coming from two gold medals.
I'm coming from nine world records
in both the two and four-man events.
I'm coming from ten years
of intense competition...
with the best athletes
in the world.
That's a hell of a place
to be comin' from.
You see, Sanka, the driver
has to work harder than anyone.
He's the first to show up
and the last to leave.
When his teammates
are all out drinkin' beer,
he's up in his room
studying pictures of turns.
You see, a driver must remain
focused 100% at all times.
Not only is he responsible for knowing
every inch of every course he races,
he's also responsible for the lives
of the other three people in his sled.
Now, do you want
that responsibility?
I say we make Derice
the driver.
So do l, Sanka. So do I.
[Sighs]
Oh. The back is nice.
[Junior]
All right, Father, listen here.
Ya see, I've made up my mind.
I am going to be a bobsledder.
That's right. A bobsledder.
- [Dog Barks, Whines]
- Oh, really?
Well, I'm sorry
you feel that way.
Fine. Cut off my allowance,
because you see, Father,
a man has got to do
what a man has got to do.
[Car Horn Honking]
- Just who I want to see.
- M-M-Me?
- You know where I just came from?
- W-Where?
I got you a job.
With Webster, Webster and Cohen,
the biggest brokerage house in Miami.
Oh, right.
Webster, Webster and Cohen.
[Chuckling] That's right.
And you start end of the month.
- Yes, but I thought that I would...
- Look.
We went along with
this track nonsense long enough.
And we agreed that it's time
to get on with your real future.
Right?
- I know...
- Right?
- Yes, sir.
- Good.
[Chuckles]
I'm gonna tell your mother.
[Chuckling]
- I guess we sure told him.
- [Whining]
Winning a bobsled race is about
one thing: the push start.
Now I know you dainty little
track stars think you're fast.
Well, heh, let's see how fast you are
when you push a 600-pound sled.
Now a respectable start time
is 5.7 seconds.
If you speed demons can't
whip off an even six-flat,
then you have a better chance of
becoming a barbershop quartet.
[Groaning]
Derice, come on! Hey!
- Junior, get in. Never mind.
- Ow!
- [Laughing]
- Come on, fellas, move it back. Let's go!
' Here on this mountain top
oh-oh '
- 14.3. No good.
- ' I've got some wild, wild life '
- 13.5. 11.7.
- ' I've got some bills to pay, oh-oh '
This is what it's all about.
This is where you win or lose the race.
Right here in the push start.
This is where you're gonna practice,
right here, right here in a Volkswagen,
you're gonna practice.
- [Yelling]
- No! Junior, quit falling down.
Come on, hustle!
Catch up to them. There you go.
Whoa. No! Do it again.
[Sanka] Whoa, whoa. Stop, Derice!
Stop! Wait for me! Wait!
I'm in! Stop!
Slow down!
[Yelling, Crashing]
Great. Very good.
Try it again.
If I've said it once,
I've said it 46 times:
Cold weather endurance is vital
to building a successful sled team.
Cold enough?
[Chuckling]
One, two, three!
[All]
Aaaah!
- ' Wild, wild life '
- [Sanka] Go! Go! Go!
- ' Here on this mountain top '
- [Sanka] Whoa! Slow down!
- ' Oh-oh "
- [Derice] Sanka, hit the brakes, man!
- I can't! It's stuck!
- [Derice] Hold on!
Look out!
[Yelling]
[Groaning]
- [Indistinct Police Radio]
- [People Chattering]
- Sanka, you dead?
- [Groaning]
Yeah, man.
[Man] What have you done to the
police unit? I should arrest you.
- [Man #2] Who owns this thing?
- We do, sir.
- And who are you?
- The Jamaican bobsled team, sir.
- [Laughing]
Don't give me that business.
I wasn't born yesterday.
5.9! 5.9! You did it!
You did it! 5.9!
We did it! We did it! 5.9!
Get outta the way! Get outta the way!
5.9, guys! What?
- Who are you?
- I'm their coach. You guys okay?
- Yeah, man.
- [Irv] How's the sled?
Sled's okay?
Well, it's in the wrong place.
Get it back to the top of the hill!
Let's move it right now, you slackers!
- Move it! Let's hustle!
Come on, you guys, move it!  - [Team Groaning]
[Thunder Rumbling]
[Irv] I'm not asking
for a winter sports program.
All I need is a lousy 20 grand so I
can get us to the Olympics. That's all.
[Coolidge] How in God's name
are you going to get to the Olympics?
These boys have never even
seen a sled race before.
Mr. Coolidge, I have been looking
at sledders since I was 12 years old.
If I say these kids can
make it to the Olympics,
they can make it to the Olympics.
Okay. Well, I'll
tell you what we'll do.
Practice down here
with the boys a bit more,
and when you're a little further along,
I'll come along and see you...
- No! No, no!
- Now just a minute, Mr. Blitzer!
This country enjoys
a fine athletic tradition.
And if you think I'm gonna give you
the little money we have...
so that you can parade us around
in front of the world like a freak show,
you've got another thing coming.
It's bad enough how you
embarrassed your own country.
I'm certainly not gonna
allow you to embarrass ours.
No go, kid.
That's okay, coach.
We'll get the money.
Do the words "give up"
mean anything to you?
Not a thing.
[Sanka] ' Some people say you know
they can't believe '
' Jamaica
we have a bobsled team '
' 'Nuff people say you know
they can't believe '
' Jamaica
we have a bobsled team "
Hi. I'm here to offer you
an opportunity of a lifetime.
We're lookin' for a sponsor
for the first Jamaican bobsled team.
[Laughing]
[Crowd Chattering]
[Crowd Cheering]
- Oh!
- [Smacks Lips]
' We have the one Derice
and the one Junior "
I'll pay you a dollar to shut up.
[Joy]
You got $9.52 from Yul Brenner.
Thank you.
We got $184 from Derice and me.
Sanka, how did your singing
on the street go?
How did it go?
It went like this.
' 'Nuff people say you know
they can't believe '
- Sanka, we know.
- ' Jamaica, we have a bobsled team '
- Sanka.
- ' We have the one Derice..."
[All]
How much?
- I made $1.16.
- [Irv] Oh, that's great.
- We're only short about 19,000 bucks.
- [Beads Rattling]
- Sorry I'm late, everybody.
- [Irv] No, really. That is terrific.
You can unpack your suitcase,
Junior. We're not goin'.
Hmm, that's too bad.
- [Sanka Whistles]
- [Derice] Whoa. Where'd you get it, man?
- I sold my car.
- [Inhales] Yes, man.
- I am goin'!
- No, we're not.
Look here, Junior, I appreciate
what you're trying to do here.
But we can't accept this money.
It just wouldn't be proper.
Aw, Derice, if I hadn't
tripped you fellas,
we'd already been goin'
to the Olympics.
I want you to have it.
You mean you want us
to have it, right?
Right. Us.
Thanks a lot, Junior.
Thanks a whole heap, man.
[Yul] Remember. This doesn't mean
that I like you. You understand?
- [Joy] Be sure to thank your father for us...
'cause Lord knows he didn't
have to let you sell that car.
Well, uh, he doesn't know
I sold the car.
Um...
[Clears Throat]
He doesn't know I'm
on the team, actually.
He thinks I'm off to Miami...
and I loaned the car
to a friend to work for...
Webster, Webster and Cohen,
some place like that.
- [All Laughing]
- ' Some people say you
know them can't believe '
' Jamaica
we have a bobsled team '
- ' We have the one Derice '
- ' And the one Junior '
' Yu... Sanka '
[Derice] ' The fastest of the fastest
of Jamaican sprinters '
' Go to Olympics
Fight for Jamaica "
[Man On P.A. Speaking French]
[Man On P.A.]
Welcome to Calgary, Alberta, Canada.
- Come on.
- Home of the 1988 Winter Olympic Games.
- This is it.
- We hope you all enjoy your stay.
Sanka, man,
what you smokin'?
[Coughing]
I'm not smokin'. I'm breathin'.
All right, fellas,
this is us. Let's go.
[Yelling]
What's the matter?
You guys cold?
It's not so much the heat,
it's the humidity that'll kill ya.
[People Chattering
In Foreign Languages]
[P.A. Announcer Speaking
Excuse me, do you know
where you register for bobsled?
[Chattering, P.A. Continue]
Do you know where
you register for bobsled?
- See ya.
- I'll see ya around.
Hey, Mike. Good to see ya
again, pal. Take care.
- Ja? Okay, ja.
- All the best.
- Can I help you?
- Yeah, I'd like to register for tryouts.
- What country?
- [Clears Throat] Jamaica.
- Jamaica.
- [Sighs]
- [Computer Beeps]
Well, what do you know?
Jamaican bobsled team.
Okay. Here it is.
It says here...
your qualifying run will be held
on the evening of the tenth.
Your judges will be Shindler,
Gremmer and Kroychzech.
- I know Kroychzech. He's a good guy.
- Yeah. [Clears Throat]
In order to qualify, you must
complete the course safely...
in one-minute,
two-seconds flat or under.
- Used to be a minute-five.
- Yeah.
Times change.
- Irv? Is that you?
- Roger, how ya doin'?
Hello, Kurt.
Been a long time.
Obviously not long enough.
Hello, Larry.
Jesus Christ, Irv.
What the hell'd you do to yourself?
- Don't worry about them, Irv.
- Roger, you gotta do me a favor.
- What?  - Please. You know that
revolving restaurant thing?
- Yeah. Half an hour?
- Meet me there in half an hour. Yeah.
- Please!
- [Man] Roger, come on!
[Roger]
I'll try.
- Thanks, Roger.
- Yeah, well. What's up, Irv?
- How about a drink?
- No, I'm fine.
What's so important it couldn't wait?
- You want something to eat?
- No, I m fine. What's up?
- A salad or something...
- Irv!
I need a sled.
You came all the way
to Calgary without a sled?
I got $4,800.
I just need something competitive.
[Laughs]
For five grand?
- I know you got something lying around,
Roger.  - But, Irv...
- Anything.
- You know I can't do that.
Wait a minute, Roger.
Remember when you were desperate...
to make that last slot
on the '68 Grenoble team,
and you pleaded with me
to talk to Kurt?
Did I say, "Sorry,
Roger, I can't do it"?
Come on, don't make me beg.
Roger, it's me.
All right. Maybe I can get you
one of our practice sleds.
You're a saint. You know that? A SAINT!
You haven't changed a bit.
You're still a saint.
Don't get all mushy on me.
Just tell me one thing.
Is this whole thing a big joke?
Or do you really expect
these Jamaicans to qualify?
Not only are they gonna qualify,
they're gonna turn some heads doin' it.
Listen, three of these guys
can run the hundred in under ten-flat.
I don't care who you are,
that's lightning.
Yeah. But can lightning run on ice?
- No problem, man.
- [Chuckles]
- God!
- [Grunting]
Irv! These special shoes
aren't very effective.
Grip with your toes.
All right, you sugarcoated
track stars.
Move out and let the ice-Rasta
show you how it's done.
- Whoa! Ah!
- Yeah, like that. Yeah. Good.
[Junior] Hey, fellas,
look at my progress.
Touchin' me!
[Grunts]
[Buzzer Buzzing]
All right, fellas, that's it.
Let's get off the ice before practice.
- What practice?
- That practice.
[Speaking Russian]
- Whoa. Ah!
- Oh!
[Grunting]
That's right. Ah!
Good team this year.
Eins, zwei, drei.
[Grunting]
Nice. Bobsleds.
Oh, my. You should see this on the hill.
It's like a miracle.
- What's "schweiz"?
- No, man, Swiss.
[Yul]
This is the real thing, man.
Gentlemen. I'd like to introduce you
to the newest member of our team.
[Irv] Uh, you won't believe
what I had to go through...
to get us a sled
in such good shape.
[Clears Throat] If we're gonna
make it into the Olympics,
this is the boat
that's gonna take us there.
Well, I'm told she's
actually quite fast.
[Metal Clattering On Floor]
- I, uh, know she's not much to look at,
but, uh...  - Shh!
She's beautiful.
[Speaking Russian]
[P.A.] All coaches must sign teams in
before approaching bob run.
- [Irv] Here we go.
- [Grunting]
[Irv]
Let's go. Here we go.
- Hold on.
- All right, come on.
[Irv]
Grab ahold. Here we go.
[Sanka]
Ah. This is good.
[Irv]
This is it. Everybody climb in.
Hold up.
I don't understand.
- We're not gonna push start?
- No, we're gonna push start next time.
For your first run,
I'm just gonna nudge you off.
Okay, everybody in. Let's go,
let's go. Come on, come on.
- [Yul] Don't touch me.
- Hey, baldy, get off my foot.
- Don't touch me!
- Here we go. Come on.
Hey, Blitzer. Why don't you put
some training wheels on that sled?
- [Crowd Laughing]
- That's funny. Ha-ha. Very funny.
- You want to kiss my egg?
- I'm not kissin' no egg.
- Suit yourself.
- [Irv] Listen up, fellas.
- I don't want you to worry about
lookin' good out there.  - Ah, Blitzy.
You're going to tuck them in too?
Hey. Seemin' to you
like nobody likes us?
We're different. People
always afraid of what's different.
Hey, Jamaica!
Watch out for number 12 turn.
It's scary, ja?
Oooh!
What's his problem?
He's Josef Grool. He's one
of the best drivers in the world.
Yeah, he's one of the biggest
assholes in the world too.
Don't listen to him; you listen to me.
Derice, right here. You got it?
Remember, keep your hands soft
and your mind clear.
- High in, low out. What is it?
- High in, low out.
All right, put your helmets on,
everybody. Let's go.
Here we go, come on.
Helmets on.
- Hey, coach?
- Yeah.
I cannot get my helmet on.
- Thanks, coach.
- That's what I'm here for.
- Oh, coach? L-I gotta go. You know.
- Yeah?
- Hold it.
- Hold it?
- Hold it!
- Yeah, hold it!
B-But, coach, l, I can't hold it.
We're not bobsledding yet.
- Oh, yes, we are.
- Coach! Coach!
Coach! Coach!
[P.A.]
On the track.
[Sanka]
Coach! Aaaaah!
Aaaaah!
Slow down! Oh!
Slow down! Slow down!
Oh, my God! Oh! Oh, Derice!
Oh, Derice! I hate you!
I hate you!
I hate you! Ohhhh!
[Sanka Yelling]
[Crashing]
[Derice]
Sanka, you dead?
Yeah, man.
Well, you can pee now.
Erm...too late.
This is embarrassing.
[Coughing]
[Yul] Man, shut down
that hot plate, fool.
Those bananas are stinkin'
like a dead dog.
Back off, back off, you eight ball!
This is my mama's secret recipe.
And I hope you don't mind keepin' quiet
while I catch up on my reading.
What are you talkin' about, readin'?
This is a children's book.
- Oh, is that so?
- Yes, that's so.
If that's a children's book, that mean's
it's too advanced for the likes of you.
What are you trying to say? That I'm
not smarter than a little child?
No. What I am saying to you is that you
are the kind of club-totin'...
raw meat-eatin',
me-Tarzan-you-Janein',
big, bald bubblehead
that can only count to ten...
if he's barefoot
or wearing sandals.
Say whatever it is
that you want.
Because you're just like
every other fool on the island.
You're going nowhere, Sanka,
and you're thrilled to death about it.
But you see me?
You see me?
I'm different
'cause I know exactly...
where I'm going.
And after l, Yul Brenner,
win the Olympics
and become famous,
I'm gonna leave the island...
and live right down there.
[Laughing]
What are you laughing about?
- What are you laughing about?
- That's Buckingham Palace.
You plan on livin' there,
you're gonna have to marry the Queen.
Yul, that's where
the Queen of England lives.
[Sanka] Face it, Yul Brenner.
You can start callin' yourself Madonna,
but you're still gonna end
up in an outhouse shanty
like every other dockworking nobody.
- Says who?
- Says me, rich boy.
What you know about it?
Well, I know my father
started off in a one-room hut.
Now, he lives in one of
the biggest homes in Kingston.
- Well, he ain't your father.
- He doesn't have to be.
All he has to do is know what
he wants and work hard for it.
And if he wants it bad enough,
he'll get it.
Look, believe me, Sanka,
the more Yul Brenners we got
makin' it in this world,
the better off this world would be.
Especially for Jamaicans.
Go ahead, Yul Brenner.
You go get your palace.
[Yelling]
Move, move!
[P.A.]
On the track.
What do you have in there, a baby?
- I can't believe you're still cold, man.
- Cold?
I'm freezin' my royal,
Rastafarian nay-nays off!
All right, we're up.
Let's go, guys. This is it.
Gimme that.
Okay. Now this is
our first real push start...
but don't worry about it, okay?
l-lt's no different than what we
practiced. We've done it a hundred times.
Derice, right here.
Okay, get your helmets on.
- Coach.
- Okay, okay.
- Thanks, coach.
- All right. Let's go, Derice. It's yours.
- Ridiculous. What's he doing?
- [Irv] Ready!
One, two, three.
- [Yelling]
- Go, go, go, go!
- [Derice] Hold on! Wait!
- Now!
- Now! Now!
- Whoa! Look out!
- Now.
- [Sanka Yelling]
[Speaking German]
Those guys are pretty good,
aren't they?
Good? They're the best.
So you guys been having a
little trouble out there, huh?
Ah, we'll be fine.
I sure hope so. It'd be a real
shame to waste all that talent.
I'm not worried.
And we have a good coach.
[Laughs]
Kid, I hate to say it,
but you gotta wake up.
Coach Blitzer's
what's killin' ya.
He's been useless
since the day he was busted.
- What you mean, "busted"?
- The '72 Games.
The guy hid weights in the front
of the sled to make it go faster.
So what?
It's no big deal.
Having your gold medals taken away
for cheating is a big deal.
Derice, let's go.
We've got a meeting.
Givin' my kid
a few pointers, Larry?
Your kid's gonna need
all the help he can get.
Coach.
[Knocking]
Maid service, sir.
Would you like your bed turned down?
Mint? Perhaps I could
dust your head.
Whatever's wrong with you...
is no little thing.
Hurry up, man. I have a dead grandmother
that moves faster than you.
- Wait, wait.
- [Knocking]
What that fool want now?
- What?
- Sorry.
- What do you have there, man?
- A telegram.
I know it's a telegram.
What's it say?
From my father.
He says I have to
come home right now.
[Sighs]
' Workin' '
' Workin' from payday
to payday '
' Every time payday comes
you know I'm down to my last '
' Well, I'm dreamin' '
' Dreamin' of you all day '
' When the working's done we're
gonna love that night away '
' 'Cause we're goin' nowhere
and we're gettin' there fast '
' When we finally make it
we can both look back '
' On these hard times '
' Just for a laugh '
- Hi.
- Howdy, partner.
' 'Cause when you got love you
don't need too much money '
' I'm in love with you
and don't you know, honey '
' We're goin' nowhere '
- ' And we're gettin' there fast '
- You've worked too hard and too long.
And let me tell you
somethin' else, Junior Bevil.
If it wasn't for you,
we wouldn't be here right now.
Wait.
But you don't understand.
He is really mad.
I mean, you don't know him
like I do, you know.
[Sighs] I think I better
just do what he wants...
and go back home.
And forget about your teammates?
Blood fire!
The man, you act like he's
the king of the whole world.
But what should I do?
What should I do?
Hey, Jamaica! Keep it down.
You are not owning this place.
Sorry, sir, sorry. I...
I didn't mean to bother anyone.
You have no business here,
Jamaica.
You and your stupid friend,
playing like you are bobsledders, ja.
Why don't you tourists go back
to where it is you came from...
and leave the bobsledding
to the real men.
Well, um, I'm a real man.
You want to say something, Jamaica?
Come on out with it.
' You know that money can't buy '
' This feelin' '
' That we're sharing tonight '
' 'Cause we're goin' nowhere
and gettin' there fast "
Come here, man.
Out. Right now!
Now, look in the mirror
and tell me what you see.
- I see Junior.
- You see Junior.
Well, you wanna know
what I see?
I see pride. I see power!
I see a badass mother who don't
take no crap off nobody!
- You really see all that?
- Yeah, man.
But it's not about what I see.
It's about what you see.
Now look in this mirror
and tell me again what you see.
[Clears Throat]
I see... [Sighing]
- Pride!
- Pride! Right.
- Power!
- Power.
- And I see...
- A badass mother...
- Who don't take no... -
- Who won't take no crap off of nobody!
- Again!
- I see pride!
-  Can't hear you!
- I see power!
I see a badass mother who won't
take no crap off of nobody!
- Once again! Junior!
- I see pride!
I see power! I see a badass mother
who won't take no crap off of nobody!
- That's right!
- That's right! Junior Bevil!
Where ya... Where he going?
Pride. Power. Pride.
Now you listen to me, buddy.
I will not be talked to that way,
so you better come up with
a damn good apology... or else.
- Or else what?
- Ow!
Eh, Jamaica?
- Or else what?
- Whoa!
Come on, Jamaica.
Say something.
No problem, man.
[People Screaming]
[Men Grunting,
Glass Breaking]
Excuse me, missy!
Yippee-ki-yay! Woohoo!
[Grunting Continues]
[Sanka] Oh, come on, that hurt.
Let me go. Oh-oh.
- [Snickering]
- I can't believe this.
I just can't believe this.
Didn't one of you have the sense
to know better? Go on, laugh.
I wanna see who's laughing
when Irv gets here.
Now, wait, wait.
When that East German fellow
go out and push my teammate,
and blood fire,
we have to fight back.
You don't see the Swiss team
fightin', do you?
drinkin' and carryin' on and such.
And you don't see the Swiss team
smilin' neither.
In fact, if one of those Swiss boys
ever come across a pretty girl,
he probably yell,
"Eins, zwei, drei,"
and try to push her down some ice.
[Laughing]
- What happened?
- Oh, I took care of the whole thing.
I told the owner of the bar
these guys were...
mentally disturbed, so he's
not gonna press any charges.
All right,
sled god does it again.
Just shut up, Sanka.
Now maybe you haven't noticed,
but we aren't exactly winning
any popularity contests here.
They hate me, they hate you,
they hate us.
Now, if we're even gonna
think about qualifying,
we're each gonna have to sit down
and take a nice, deep look inside.
I didn't come all this way
to get my butt whipped.
As a matter of fact, now that I'm here,
I thought I'd do
a little whipping of my own.
Good night, gentlemen.
- [Door Opening]
- [Clock Ticking]
- [Alarm Ringing]
- Aaah!
- Rise and shine.
- It's butt-whipping time.
" [Whistling]
" ["Rise Above lt"
By Lock, Stock And Barrel]
' Rise above it '
- Not bad. Pick it up though.
- " [Continues]
Come on, come on, come on, come on!
Now, now, now, now!
' Just rise above it '
' Come on then
Rise above it '
- Good. That's it.  - ' Even though the road
seems very long and narrow '
- Five more. Come on, five more.
- ' Baby need to sharpen his pin '
- Push it, push it, come on.
That's it, that's it.  - ' Just like an arrow '
- That's it. Good, good.
- ' Got-a no place to go '
- Good. You're doin' fine. You got any more?
- ' Believe us baby '
Come on, come on. Get in!
Oh! Hey!
[Grunting]
- ' You gotta learn to believe in yourself, yeah '
- [Grunting]
' This, little man, is what you can
achieve if you work hard and sacrifice '
- ' If you've got a problem '
- [Whistle Blows]
- ' You've got to rise above it Yes you do '
- Go, go, go, go. That's it.
- ' And when you face a challenge '
- Gotta grip with your toes!
- ' You've got to rise above it It's so large '
- Go, go, go! Now, now!
' If those storm clouds reappear
Oh, yes '
- [Grunting Continues]
- ' You don't never have to fear. Just rise above it '
' You, you've got to
rise above it '
- [Grunting Continues]
- ' I tell ya once and I tell ya twice '
You're gonna have to do this
on your own one day.
' Come now, come now
and take my advice '
' Rise above it '
- [Grunts]
- ' Rise above it '
[Irv] Go, go, go, go, go!
Now, now, now, now, now!
- Straight. Right.
- Turn six.
- Turn seven. Turn eight.
- Straight. Right.
- ' Follow me, follow me, follow me follow me,
rise above it '  - That's it, that's it!
' Rise above it '
" [Singing In Jamaican]
' Rise above it
You can do it '
You can do it "
[Irv]
Okay, guys,
tonight's the night.
Now, in a few minutes,
you're gonna get a chance
to do something that no one
in your country has ever done.
I was gonna save this for the Olympics,
but I figure if we're going to convince
these judges that we are world-class sledders,
then we had better look
like world-class sledders.
- Oh, man, yes.
- Oh, man. Nice.
I freeze in this.
[Grunting, Yelling]
[P.A.]
On the track.
Hello, gentlemen.
Irv, this is Karl Shindler.
He'll be watching the middle track.
How do you do?
- And this is August Gremmer.
He'll be judging the push starts.
- Hi.
- I'm your third official up in the tower.
You? What happened
to Kroychzech?
He came down sick this morning.
I'm taking his place.
Oh, goody.
Oh. The Alliance has decided
to change the qualifying time...
from a minute-two
to a minute-flat.
Is that clear?
[Jamaican Accent]
No problem, man.
Go get 'em, kid.
[On Speaker]
Track is clear for Jamaica One.
Eins... zwei... drei.
[Grunting, Yelling]
Go, go, go!
Now, now, now, now!
- All right, what was that time?
- 6.13
Under 60. Is it under 60?
- [Cheering]
- Yes! Derice... Bannock!
Whoo-hoo, 59 points!
[Laughing]
Oh. I'm, uh, I'm sorry.
I'm outta here. That's terrific.
- [Laughing Continues]
- [Cheering Continues]
Derice!
- " [Reggae]
- [Irv] Ah, it was great.
[Derice] They couldn't beat us.
I know we were the best.
[Irv]
...inspired you guys, that's all.
Nobody had that much fun
in a sled since Santa Claus.
Fellas, here's
to followin' your dreams.
- Yeah, man.
- [Together] Followin' your dreams.
I said it to your father the first time
I met him, and I'll say it again.
- Sprinters make the best bobsledders.
- Here's to sprinting.
So, what are we gonna
name the sled?
How about "Tallulah"?
- [Laughter]
- Tallulah.
Tallulah.
Sounds like a two-dollar hooker.
How you come up with that?
Hey, you idiot,
that's my mother's name.
- It's a pretty name.
- Tallulah. I like that.
So, what's it gonna be, star?
What are the people gonna be screamin'
when Jamaica takes the hill?
I say we call it
"Cool runnings."
- [Yul] Beautiful.
- I like it.
- It's very strong.
- Nice. Very nice.
Uh, what exactly does it mean?
"Cool runnings" means
"Peace be the journey."
[Together]
Peace be the journey.
- Cool runnings.
- [Together] Cool runnings.
- [Clears Throat] Excuse me.
- To the man in the orange suit!
[Laughing, Shouting]
- To the messenger!
- [Together] To the messenger.
[Laughing, Shouting Continue]
[Sighing]
We are officially...
disqualified.
- [Chattering, Laughing]
- Excuse me, gentlemen.
Kurt, I really
have to talk to you.
Excuse me, Irv.
I've nothing to say to you.
Yes, you do. I want to know
why you disqualified my guys.
As you were told, your team must
compete in an international race
in order to qualify for the Olympics.
But in an Olympic year, the qualifiers
count as an international race.
That may have been true
in past Olympic years,
but this year the Alliance
decided to change its policy.
Oh, please.
Change its policy?
The Alliance has the right to
do whatever they feel is in their...
...best interest of the sport.
We must also be concerned about
the potential for embarrassment.
Oh, forgive me.
I didn't realize that four black guys
in a bobsled could make you blush.
[Shindler]
I think we've heard enough.
Come on, Kurt. What you're doin'
is wrong and you know it.
Now, if this is about you and me,
then let's get it straight right now.
All right, 16 years ago,
I made the biggest mistake of my life.
I cheated. I was stupid.
I embarrassed myself,
my family,
my teammates, my country
and my coach.
If it's revenge you want,
take it.
Go ahead.
Disqualify me, banish me.
Do whatever you want,
but do it to me.
It was me who let you down, Kurt.
It wasn't my guys.
They've done everything
you've asked of them.
And they did it with all of you
laughing in their face.
Hell, it doesn't matter
if they come in first or 50th.
Those guys have earned the right
to represent their country.
They've earned the right
to march into that stadium...
and wave their nation's flag.
That's the single greatest honor
an athlete could ever have.
That's what the Olympics
are about.
Sixteen years ago,
I forgot that.
Don't you go and do the same.
[Sighing] I'm sorry
if I interrupted your meeting.
[Ringing]
Hello? Yes.
Yeah.
Right. Good-bye.
- What?
- Oh, it's the Alliance. God.
What did they say?
Aw, they said we're back in.
[Cheering]
Yes! Yes, yes!
[Cheering Continues]
[Man On Television] And a lot
is expected of the Italian team.
Did I miss it? Did I miss it?
No, child,
you didn't miss a thing.
[Broadcast Continues]... of Jamaica
made it all the way here to Calgary...
to compete in the bobsled event.
Their flag bearer is
the sled captain Derice Bannock.
Derice's father, Ben Bannock,
was a gold medalist in the 200 meters...
at the Summer Olympic Games
over 20 years ago.
And perhaps there's gold
in two generations of this family.
That's quite a story.
The Jamaican bobsled team.
It's a beautiful afternoon in Calgary,
and there is a lot more coming up.
So stay tuned for more exciting
coverage of the opening ceremonies...
of the 15th Winter Olympiad
from Calgary, Alberta, Canada.
Gentlemen, let's go check
into our new home. Come on, Junior.
[Irv]
Junior! Hey!
Junior!
Now, a lot of coaches
would be giving you one of those...
"Win one for the Gipper" speeches.
I'm not good at that stuff.
Instead, I thought I'd, uh,
lead you in a psalm of inspiration.
Let's bow our heads.
- Who's the "Gipper"?
- Shh.
Our Father who art in Calgary,
bobsled be Thy name.
Thy kingdom come,
gold medals won...
- [Giggling]
- On Earth as it is in turn seven.
With liberty and justice
for Jamaica and Haile Selassie.
- Amen.
- All right.
- Respect.
- [Knock At Door]
- All right.
- Jah Rastafari.
[Chattering]
[Chattering Continues]
Junior?
Now, you listen to me, boy.
You might not have done
what you were asked,
but you will do
what you're told.
- You're coming home.
- But, Father, you know I just want...
But nothing.
I didn't send you
to the finest school...
for you to go around
sliding on your backside.
- You must be mad.
- Yeah, but the team needs me.
- I don't want to hear any more about it.
- [Elevator Bell Rings]
Go and get your things.
I'll wait in the lobby.
- [Elevator Bell Rings]
- Pride. Power.
Father, when you look at me,
what do you see?
- I don't have time for games, Junior.
- Tell me what you see, please!
All right,
I'll tell you what I see.
I see a lost little boy...
who's lucky to have a father
who knows what's best for him.
[Elevator Bell Rings]
No, no, no, no, you don't know
what's best for me, Father.
I am not a lost little boy,
Father.
I am a man.
And I'm an Olympian.
I'm stayin' right here.
[Elevator Bell Rings]
Hey, Junior Bevil.
You're a badass mother.
[Chattering]
- Here, I got a couple.
- I like this one, yes.
[Foreign Languages]
Oh, Canada, indeed. This is Al Trautwig
along with John Morgan.
We're live at Olympic Park,
the brand-new bobsledding venue...
just a few miles outside
of downtown Calgary.
- Everybody, shut up. It's starting.
- ...extremely intense,
exciting competition
for the next three days.
[Chattering]
I am feeling very Olympic today.
How about you?
[Al Trautwig On TV] This sport, as we
well know, is made up of athletes...
who go to the edge and sometimes beyond,
and it is why we believe...
the next three days is going to be
extremely competitive and exciting.
And already, John, on day one, we're starting
things off with a gold medal favorite.
Well, the Swiss were fortunate enough
to draw number one in the competition.
We gotta make them the odds-on favorite
to win the gold.
But the East Germans, they're coming off
the gold medal win in 1984.
The Canadians, it's their home track.
You gotta favor them too.
And they've been doin'
very well in practice all week.
[Shouting In German]
- Eins, zwei, drei.
- [Grunting]
- [Cheering]
One, two, three, go!
[Cheering Continues]
[Al Trautwig On TV]
Eighty miles an hour or close to it.
You know, Al, I'm looking at the times here,
and the course is gettin' extremely fast.
I was worried about the Austrian
team's safety in that last big
180 degree whiparound that draws
4 G's of Force from the athletes.
Well, if you were worried about them,
what are you thinking about
our last and next team?
Yes, it certainly seems strange that
surrounded by the ice and snow of Calgary,
we are about to watch a team
from the tiny island of Jamaica.
- [Cheering]
- Yeah, from Jamaica!
Quite a story for them to even get here.
They came out of nowhere.
And you know, there's a lot of teams
up here on top of the hill...
that sort of feel that Jamaicans
don't belong here.
[Booing]
- Hey! Hey! What are you doin'?
- Hey, what are you doin', man?
That's what the Swiss do
to psyche themselves up.
They also make them little pocket knives,
too, but I don't see you doin' that.
All right, guys, we're up. Come on.
Hey, knock it off. Knock it off, will ya?
Okay, let's go. Come on.
Get in your start positions.
We don't have to win the gold in the
first day. It's just like any other run.
Except this time,
100 million people watchin'.
[Irv] Derice, did you forget
something? Thank you.
- Ready.
- [Sanka] Ready.
- [Junior] Ready.
Eins... zwei...
drei.
Go! Go, go, go!
Go! Go!
- [Crowd Cheering, Indistinct P.A.]
- Get in! Get in!
[Al] The Jamaican team attempts
its first ever Winter Olympic event.
[Chuckling] And look at this.
They've got to get into that sled.
Now I've never seen anything like this.
I know it's not funny,
but how embarrassing.
Thank goodness. For a minute, I didn't
think they'd ever get all four of them in.
And that could have been
a disaster.
[Cheering, Shouting]
[John Morgan] Well, most importantly
here, when you do get in the sled,
you have to get in with catlike
movements; you need to get relaxed.
Look at the high line in Omega!
He bounces off the wall,
ricochets like a pinball.
The driver here, Derice Bannock, looks
like the sled's really drivin' him.
- That fool better watch his mouth.
- He better watch more than that.
This is the time when
this team may be thinking,
"This may not have
been such a great idea."
Their heads are bouncing around.
This is amazing.
Like rag dolls as they
come through the finish...
at a time of 58.04,
which will be good enough
for last place.
[Quiet Chattering]
You choked. It was yours
for the taking and you choked.
You were ready and you choked.
Well, maybe we should
go over the turns again?
You know the turns.
You know everything there
is to know about this sport.
I'll tell you something.
You had all better figure out
how to stay loose out there.
That's something
I can't help you with.
I'll see you tomorrow
on the hill.
[Door Opens, Closes]
- You know...
- when the Swiss want to get relaxed...
- [Groaning]
Oh, will you shut up
about the damn Swiss?
I mean, it was all that
"eins, zwei, drei" nonsense
that got us all nervous
in the first place.
Hey, man, look here. I'm just tryin'
to get us off on the right foot.
Well, the right foot for
us is not the Swiss foot.
I mean, come on, Derice.
We can't be copyin' nobody else's style.
We have our own style.
Kissin' an egg is no kind of style.
This is the Olympics here.
It's no stupid pushcart derby.
Let me tell ya somethin', Rasta.
I didn't come up here to forget
who I am and where I come from.
And neither did I.
I'm just tryin' to be the best I can be.
So am I. And the best
I can be is Jamaican.
Look.
Derice, I've known you since Julie
Jeffries asked to see your ding-a-ling.
And I'm tellin' you
as a friend...
if we look Jamaican,
walk Jamaican,
talk Jamaican and is Jamaican,
then we sure as hell
better bobsled Jamaican.
[Chattering, Shouting]
- [Derice] Greetings from Jamaica.
- " [Reggae]
' 'Nuff people say you know
they can't believe '
' Jamaica, we have a bobsled team '
' 'Nuff people say you know
they can't believe '
' Jamaica, we have a bobsled team '
' We have the one Derice
and the one Junior '
- Thank you.
- ' Yul Brenner and the man Sanka '
' The fastest of the fastest
of Jamaica's sprinters '
' Respect to the man
Irv Blitzer "
- All right, gentlemen, this is it.
- [Together] Respect.
- All right.
- Whoo, let's go!
[Al] We now come to the second chance
for the four intrepid men from Jamaica.
What do they have to do, John?
In reality, Al, I don't think the Jamaicans
have any chance of winning a medal.
Dear God, just let them
be better than yesterday.
- Ready?
- Ready.
Feel the rhythm, feel the rhyme,
get on up, it's bobsled time!
- Cool runnings!
- [Crowd Cheering]
[P.A.]
On the track.
[John] That's a hair
faster than the Swiss.
That's a real big
difference from yesterday.
[Al] This is an absolute
shock in the making.
Yesterday, they were
falling down at the start.
- Yes!
- Now they slide into place.
Yesterday, their heads
were bobbing everywhere.
Today they're almost in unison.
- [Al] Can this really be happening?
- What a difference!
Flying through the Omega,
looking posessed here.
It's not the same team we saw yesterday.
- Where did these guys come from?
- [Together] Jamaica!
[Cheering, Shouting]
Wow, 56.53!
Whoo! Yes! Yes!
Did you hear that time?
- Yeah.
- Yes! Ha-ha!
Whoo-hoo! Yes! Yes!
Come on, teammates.
- Jamaica!
- Yes! Yes!
- [Cheering]
- [John] That moves them
up into eighth place.
[Al] Watch out, world,
the Jamaicans are coming.
Derice, you in here?
Hey, coach.
Oh, there you are.
How're ya feelin'?
- All right.
- Good, good.
- You all set to follow
in your father's footsteps?
- I think so.
- You think so?
- All right, I know so.
That's more like it.
We're gonna go grab a bite to eat.
You wanna join us?
- Nah.
- I didn't think so. I'll
pick you somethin' up.
- Hey, coach.
- Yeah.
- I have to ask you a question.
- Sure.
But you don't have to answer
if you don't want to.
I mean, I want you to, but...
if you can't, I understand.
- You want to know why I cheated, right?
- Yes, I do.
That's a fair question.
It's quite simple, really.
I had to win.
You see, Derice,
I'd made winning my whole life.
And when you make winning your whole life,
you have to keep on winning.
No matter what.
You understand that?
No, I don't understand, coach.
You had two gold medals.
You had it all.
Derice... a gold medal
is a wonderful thing.
But if you're not enough
without it,
you'll never be enough with it.
Hey, coach...
how will I know if I'm enough?
When you cross that finish line,
you'll know.
[Door Opens, Closes]
Welcome back to the
bobsledding venue for this,
the last day of competition. It's medal time,
and John, the top six teams
are separated by only half a second.
- So it's very close.
- I didn't expect to see you here.
Well, my dear, we've got a team
in the Olympics, don't we?
The Jamaicans still have a chance
to win an Olympic medal.
Everybody shut up.
My boy's on TV.
And you're not the only one
to get excited about that.
I think the fans here have
an extreme case of Jamaican fever.
- Al, so do I.
- Oh, no, no, no, no. So do we.
Do I have to tell you
whose turn it is now?
- Jamaica to your start positions.
- [Together] Respect!
Hey, dreadlocks,
let me kiss your lucky egg.
[P.A.]
Next team up is Jamaica.
All right, fellas, that's us!
Let's go!
Here we go! Today's our day!
This is it!
Come on, guys, we can do it!
Derice...
see you at the finish line.
All right, it's all yours!
Let's go!
[Al] We might actually see
the Jamaicans win an Olympic medal.
So this is it.
We could see history in the making.
Feel the rhythm, feel the rhyme,
get on up, it's bobsled time.
- Cool runnings!
- [P.A.] On the track.
- [Cheering]
- Go! Go!
Go! Move! Go!
Move that bobsled! Go!
[Al] One, two, three, four,
all of them in, and look at them fly.
[John] Oh, man, they shaved another
couple hundredths off the start.
Al, they get better
every time down the track.
Go, Derice! Move!
Take that bobsled! Move!
[John] Look at the way the sled's coming
in and out of the corners. Very smooth.
It's like he's been driving
the sled for ten years.
Bannock looks really possessed here.
[Al]
Well, what the heck. Go, Jams!
What a run Bannock is having.
He's letting loose
on this extremely fast course.
And even with that rickety old sled,
the Jamaicans are flying through the turns.
This does not look good.
Something's gotta be wrong.
The Jamaicans on a record pace as they
fly almost out of control around the turn.
- Move! Move that sled!
- Now the speed seems too much,
and I don't think he's going
to be able to hold it. Oh!
Derice, you dead?
No, man, I'm not dead.
We have to finish the race.
Excuse me, please.
Excuse me.
[Crowd Cheering]
Sehr gut, Jamaica. We'll see you
in four years, ja?
Yeah, man.
Junior Bevil.
- But it doesn't mean that I like you.
- We split.
- Thanks, Irv.
- Thank you.
- [Laughing]
- All right.
Coach, coach.
Hey, guys. I'm so proud of you guys.
You all right?
Gentlemen, can I get
a picture, please?
THE JAMAICAN BOBSLED TEAM RETURNED
TO THEIR COUNTRIES AS HEROES.
FOUR YEARS LATER, THEY RETURNED
TO THE OLYMPICS...AS EQUALS.
" ["I Can See Clearly Now"
By Jimmy Cliff]
' I can see clearly now '
' The rain is gone '
' I can see all obstacles '
' In my way '
' Gone are the dark clouds '
' That had me blind '
' It's gonna be a bright '
' Bright sunshiney day '
' Oh, yes, I can make it now '
' The pain is gone '
' All of the bad feelings '
' Have disappeared '
' Here is that rainbow '
' I've been praying for '
' It's gonna be a bright '
' Bright sunshiney day '
' Look all around '
' There's nothing but blue skies '
' Look straight ahead '
' There's nothing but blue skies "
" ["Jamaican Bobsled Chant"
By Worl-A-Girl]
' Hey, no people can believe '
' Jamaica have a bobsled team '
' We have no snow
Just food and water '
' And the temperature ranges
from hot to hotter '
' No Spring, no Fall
Much less no Winter '
' And yet we have a bobsled team '
' Holding on to an Olympic dream '
' We say them ready, I'm always sayin'
them ready, them ready like Freddy '
' You see them pullin' the sled
You see the world steady '
' When they make the motion
Them a rock and a dolly '
' A country on a sled
with a wish in them body '
' Yes, my four men
are my bobsled posse '
' Yul Brenner, Derice, Junior
Sanka, the men are ready '
' When them reach the Olympics
we're proud and irie, irie, irie '
' Lord, no people can believe '
' Jamaica have a bobsled team '
' Boy, no people can believe '
' Lord, no people can believe '
' Jamaica have a bobsled team '
' Boy, no people can believe '
' Oooh "